Phillip Simmonds

Web development & Animation

15 Sirius Cove Rd, Mosman NSW 2088, Australia +61418277239 phillip.j.simmonds@gmail.com

Personal Site: http://www.phillipsimmonds.com/ LinkedIn: http://au.linkedin.com/in/phillipsimmonds GitHub: https://github.com/pjsim

Portfolio

Websites

http://hire.sydneydevcamp.com/users/phillip-simmonds

My profile on the Sydney Dev Camp hiring book shows a handful of websites and apps that I worked on developing both alone and in a team. My immediate goal is to greatly improve on my web development skills and become a capable developer.

Animation http://vimeo.com/phillipsimmonds

I have worked as a Render Wrangler for Animal Logic on their production of *The Lego Movie*. I have also done various freelancing work, particularly for business animations.

Skills

Web Development & IT

- Ruby on Rails
- Sinatra
- JQuery & Javascript
- HTML & CSS
- Git
- AWS & Heroku
- Rspec
- Python
- D3
- Processing

3D Animation

- Maya & MEL
- Nuke
- Houdini & Mantra
- Realflow
- Mental Ray & Vray

Languages

- French (Intermediate written & spoken)
- Italian (Beginner written & spoken)

Professional Experience

Render Wrangler Animal Logic, 2013

Working on *The Lego Movie* I performed various Render Wrangler tasks ranging from fixing errors, script writing (python, javascript and linux bash) and GUI/tool construction.

Freelance Animation 2010 - 2013

I completed various freelance work from 3D to business animations during my studies. Projects ranged from 3D to 2D, paid work as well as pro bono work to help out on friends' projects.

3D Layout Internship Onyx Studio Luxembourg, 2010

While travelling overseas I came across the opportunity for a short internship doing 3D animation layouts for a new television series.

Packaging/Store Hand Princeton Publishing, 2009

Casual work involving the preparation and packaging of medical manuals for health practitioners.

Retail Liquorland, 2007 - 2008

Standard POS duties such as serving customers at the register, cleaning and handling stock as well as finding the right wine for their meal at nearby BYO restaurants.

Education

Sydney Dev Camp 2013

This intensive Ruby on Rails course was my first exposure to Rails and it really solidified my previous programming experiences, making me more comfortable using MVC frameworks and with programming in general.

Advanced Diploma in Screen & Media 2011 - 2012
Academy of Interactive Entertainment

After playing around with various 3D software I decided to pursue a full-time course in film animation to indulge this new passion. As a result I gained a better understanding of computer software and by using programming to build tools for these softwares I was opened up to a new field in IT.

Bachelor of Arts & Science (B.A.S.) , Digital Cultures Major 2006 - 2010 University of Sydney

I acheived a distinction average in this generalist degree involving many different subjects where I had the opportunity to learn from different faculties from IT to language to Law and Economics.

IDEM & ALFMED, Perpignan, France 2009

During a short trip overseas I found myself learning French at these two schools in the south of France.

Certificates

Certificate of Completion, 2013 Sydney Dev Camp

Certificate of Internship (Certificat de stage), 2010 Onyx Studio, Luxembourg

Masterclass CA3D Certificate, 2010 IDEM, Perpignan

Preliminary First Aid Certificate, 2001 First Aid Plus Australia Pty. Ltd, Sydney

Responsible Service of Alcohol Program, 2006
Responsible Conduct of Gambling, 2006
Alex Beaumont Hospitality Training College, Sydney

References

References available on request